luther.edu 2018-09-07

# Privacy | Luther College

____

Protecting the privacy of your personal information is important to Luther College. We respect your right to privacy and recognize our obligation to keep information about you secure and confidential. We have implemented appropriate technological safeguards and usage policies to ensure that the personal information you submit to Luther College is used only for official college business.

Luther College receives your personal information solely for the purpose of establishing and maintaining our relationship with you. For that relationship to proceed as effectively and conveniently as possible, we use technology to manage and maintain your information. We will not sell, rent, or share your personal information with other individuals, private or public organizations for any purpose outside official college business. We will not share your personal information with any unauthorized third parties.

The Luther College privacy policy defines personal information as information about you that identifies you and that is not available from public sources, such as your date of birth, your Social Security Number, or an unlisted telephone number.

Our sources of personal information about you include, but are not limited to, the following:

  * Information we receive from you on admissions applications, correspondence, communications, and other forms.
  * Information received from schools you attend or formerly attended, or to which you have applied for admission.

We do not disclose any personal information about you to anyone, except as permitted by law. For example, we share such information with the U.S. Department of Education and state agencies. We are permitted by law to disclose personal information about you to "nonaffiliated third parties" in certain circumstances; for example, we may share your personal information as necessary to administer a transaction you have requested or to process a service on your behalf.

We restrict access to your personal information to our employees who need to know the information in order to provide service to you, such as processing your application for admission. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in compliance with federal regulations to safeguard your personal information.

## Privacy Online

Luther College considers privacy, security, and service in our online operations to be just as critical as in the rest of our operations. We therefore employ all of the safeguards described above, along with the following Internet-specific practices.

Luther College uses a variety of proven protections to maintain the security of visitors information. For example, we make use of secure socket layer connections, firewall technology and encryption to protect your information.

When you visit Luther Colleges website, we may collect technical and navigational information, such as computer browser type, Internet protocol address, pages visited, and average time spent on our websites. This information may be used, for example, to alert you to software compatibility issues, or it may be analyzed to improve our web design and function.

Luther College uses demographic information gathered through Google Analytics, including its Demographics and Interests reports, to gain a deeper understanding of who our visitors are, what they are interested in, and how they are using our website.

In addition, as you browse our website, advertising cookies may be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. This allows our display advertising partners to present you with targeted advertising on other sites based on your previous interactions with our websites.

We may also use the information we collect from you to:

  * Understand your interest in Luther College as part of our admission process
  * Send you emails related to your interest in Luther College
  * Administer surveys and other site features
  * Track our advertising on third-party websites

In the event that Luther College becomes aware that site security is compromised or nonpublic user information has been disclosed to unrelated third parties as a result of external activity, including but not limited to external security attacks, we shall take reasonable measures which we deem appropriate, including but not limited to internal investigation and reporting, and notification to and cooperation with law enforcement authorities, notwithstanding other provisions of this Privacy Statement.

If Luther College becomes aware that a user's personal information provided to Luther College has been disclosed in a manner not in accordance with this Privacy Statement, we shall make reasonable efforts to notify the affected user, as soon as reasonably possible and as permitted by law, of what information has been disclosed, to the extent that we know this information.

While this Privacy Statement expresses Luther College's standards for maintenance of private data, it is not in a position to guarantee that the standards will always be met. There may be factors beyond our control that may result in disclosure of data. As a consequence, we disclaim any warranties or representations relating to maintenance or nondisclosure of private information.
